welcome to another darktable tutorial in
欢迎来到中的另一个暗表教程
this video we'll be doing drawn and
这段视频我们将绘制和
parametric masks together so in past
参数遮罩在一起 所以在过去
tutorials we've learned how to draw just
我们已经学过如何绘画的教程
a certain shape or a path over an image
图像上的某一形状或路径
and then apply that module just to that
然后将该模块仅应用于此
portion we've also learned how to do
部分我们还学会了如何做
parametric masks where we come over here
我们在这里看到的参数掩码
and we under the blend mode we go to
我们在混合模式下进入
just parametric masks and then we can
只需要参数掩码 然后我们就可以
select based on either a certain hue if
如果出现以下情况 则基于某个色调进行选择
we do hue we can constrict to just the
我们做色调 我们可以限制在
blues in this image we drag this over
蓝调在这张图中我们把这个拖到
and we just get the blues in this image
我们在这张图片中看到了忧郁的情绪
and this happens to be what we're doing
而这恰好就是我们正在做的
Oh cover correct
哦 封面是正确的
so our mask would look like this in this
所以我们的面具应该是这个样子的
case and as we fine-tune and adjust this
当我们对此进行微调和调整时
we can get it more narrow and just
我们可以把它变得更窄 更公正
select some certain blues but the
选择一些特定的布鲁斯 但
problem with this is we're selecting the
问题是我们选择的是
blues in the car and the Blues on the
车里的布鲁斯和车上的布鲁斯
ground but also the Blues in the sky so
地面上还有天空中的忧郁
when we apply our adjustment it might
当我们应用我们的调整时 可能
make our whole image it kind of throws
让我们的整个形象有点像是抛出
off what we're trying to do maybe
也许我们正在尝试做的事情
because whatever this car does also the
因为无论这辆车做什么
sky would do so in this video we're
在这段视频中 天空将会这样做
going to do a drawn and parametric mask
我要做一个绘制的参数蒙版
and we're not going to do the color
而且我们不会把这个颜色
corrector maybe we'll do color contrast
改正者也许我们会做色彩对比
so let me turn off that color corrector
所以让我关掉颜色校正器
and under color contrast here I'm going
在色彩对比下 我要走了
to go to the blend mode and we'll do
转到混合模式 我们将
drawn and parametric masks what this is
绘制遮罩和参数遮罩这是什么
going to let us do is mask off a certain
我们要做的就是戴上某种面具
area and I'll just choose the vehicle
我就选这辆车吧
and I'll do a path this time so we'll
这次我要走一条路 这样我们就
select this right here and we'll just
在这里选择这个 我们只需
come over and start clicking so I'll
过来开始点击 这样我就会
click a couple times right in here and I
在这里点击几下 我就会
should probably get a little bit more
可能会得到更多一点
exact than this but I can always fine
比这更准确 但我总是可以很好
tune this later as well and then when
以后再调 然后什么时候调
I'm done I'll right click and then the
我完成了 我将右键单击 然后
feather I can come and just feather that
羽毛我可以来给你羽毛
in really really really tight and even
穿得很紧很均匀
the whole shape I can kind of bring in
我能带来的整个造型
and I can drag and move it around by
我可以通过拖拽和移动它
left click and hold so that's not too
左键点击并按住 这样就不会太过
bad and now whatever we do so if we do
现在不管我们做什么 如果我们这样做了
this adjustment now it'll make
这一调整现在它将进行
adjustments to only the car and
仅调整到赛车和
everything else is unaffected well this
其他一切都不受影响
is the same thing that we've really done
就是我们真正做过的事情
with our with just a drawn this is
我们只打了一场平局
essentially only a
基本上只有一个
drawn masks but the nice part is now we
画出的面具 但现在最好的部分是我们
can also select certain elements within
还可以选择中的某些元素
here so as you see when we make an
在这里 正如您看到的 当我们制作
adjustment here it's also making an
这里的调整也在做出一个
adjustment within the headlight whoa
前大灯内的调整哇！
here and so we're kind of adjusting
我们在某种程度上正在调整
colors in there well what if we just
颜色在那里如果我们只是
want to select the blue I'm sorry we
我想选蓝色的 对不起 我们
just want to select the blue in here
我只想选这里的蓝色
we'll use our parametric selection in
我们将在中使用参数选择
addition to our drawn selection so to do
除了我们的抽签选择外 这样做
that we come over here and we see we
我们来到这里 我们看到我们
have options for a drawn mask but we
有绘制的面具可供选择 但我们
also have right below that the options
还有就在下面的选项
for parametric masks so we can select
用于参数遮罩 因此我们可以选择
hue now and we want we can grab our
现在色调 我们想要我们可以抓住我们的
color picker tool and kind of drag that
颜色选择器工具和拖拽的种类
in there just to get an indicator of
只是为了得到一个指示器
where that falls on our input notice is
这落在我们的输入通知上的地方是
different on input and output because
在输入和输出上不同 因为
we've made an adjustment there so
我们在那里做了调整 所以
because we've made an adjustment already
因为我们已经做了调整
in here that's affecting where this line
在这里 这会影响这条线的位置
falls that's kind of the difference so a
这是一种不同之处 所以
lot of times when if you play with this
很多时候 当你玩这个的时候
very first you're gonna not the changes
首先你要做的不是改变
you make on output an input or gonna be
将输出设置为输入 否则将成为
the same but once you've already made
同样的 但一旦你已经做出了
some changes then your input and output
然后对您的输入和输出进行一些更改
are going to be different anyway I'll be
将会是不同的 无论如何我会是
working off at the input we'll just drag
在输入端工作时 我们只需拖动
this right here and we'll select and
就在这里 我们将选择和
we'll toggle this view so we can see
我们将切换此视图 这样我们就可以看到
what our mask is looking like and so now
我们的面具是什么样子 所以现在
this is what our mash was looking like
这就是我们做的泥的样子
before it already looked pretty good
在此之前它看起来已经很不错了
because it was just everything within
因为它只是内在的一切
completely yellow within that drawn
在那幅画里完全是黄色的
shape that we made but now if we adjust
塑造了我们曾经的样子 但现在如果我们调整
this a little bit we can sort of get
这是我们可以得到的一点
some definition in there and maybe break
其中有一些定义 也许会打破
out like the wheels and the windows and
就像轮子和窗户一样
see some of that stuff a little bit
看一些这样的东西
separately so that's what I'll do is
所以这就是我要做的
drag this in and try to get this in
把这个放进去 试着把它放进去
again we're on hue so we're we're kind
再一次 我们在色调上 所以我们很友善
of trying to narrow in on the hue of
试图缩小范围的色调
this vehicle and that might be pretty
这辆车和那辆车可能很漂亮
good there we do get some of that but
很好 我们确实有一些这样的东西 但是
some of that's gonna be reflections in
其中一些将会反映在
the glass anyway so we want to change
不管怎么说 玻璃 所以我们想换一下
make an adjustment to that and then I
调整一下 然后我
can actually click on my mask let's go
可以点击我的面具了我们走吧
back to my drawn mask so I'll go to it
回到我画好的面具上 所以我会继续
in my mask manager and I'll just adjust
在我的面具管理器里 我会调整
this a little bit now that we're looking
这是我们现在正在寻找的一点
at it we're seeing sort of the ground
在那里 我们看到了一种地面
there is being affected so we can
正在受到影响 所以我们可以
fine-tune this a little bit better so
微调一下 这样就好了
that we're not so that we're getting
我们没有这样做 所以我们得到了
more it looks
看起来更像是
little bit more realistic maybe more
更现实一点 也许更现实一点
accurate to what we're trying to do okay
准确到我们想要做的事情好的
let's leave it just like that and now
让我们就这样离开吧 现在
the changes that we make all we've done
我们所做的一切改变
really has just affected our masks we've
真的影响了我们的口罩
created a more accurate mask by
通过以下方式创建更精确的蒙版
selecting the object and then using the
选择该对象 然后使用
parametric to select pixels within that
参数以选择该参数中的像素
object common pixels and now we can use
对象的公共像素 现在我们可以使用
the color correct to make adjustment and
颜色校正以进行调整和
it's only going to make adjustments to
它只会做出调整
the pixels within that selected area so
选定区域内的像素
this particular one's not giving us too
这个特别的没有给我们太多
much of an effect the the color contrast
很大程度上影响了色彩的对比度
I should have picked a better one to do
我应该选一个更好的
an example but really a lot of times
这是一个例子 但实际上很多时候
when if you're trying to change the
如果您想要更改
color there's a better way to do this so
有一个更好的方法来做这件事
this would just be making a subtle
这只会使一个微妙的
adjustment here anyway and so we can see
不管怎样 在这里进行调整 我们可以看到
what it would look like before and after
它之前和之后会是什么样子
sort of the changes that we've made but
我们所做的一些改变 但是
if we're trying to do color adjust to
如果我们尝试将颜色调整到
check out the next tutorial we're learn
查看我们正在学习的下一个教程
how to do our color zones and that's how
如何做我们的色带 这就是为什么
we can create a look sort of like this
我们可以创建一个类似这样的外观
where we can take something that was one
在那里我们可以拿到曾经的东西
color and change it to another color by
颜色 并将其更改为另一种颜色
just adjusting colors within the color
只是在颜色中调整颜色
zone module anyway hopefully that didn't
无论如何 希望它没有
make things too much more confusing for
让事情变得更加混乱
you using drawn and parametric it really
你使用绘图和参数化
is fairly simple where you just draw a
是相当简单的 你只需画一个
shape and then apply parametric's width
形状 然后应用参数宽度
to anything within that shape or that
任何在这种形状或
mask but knowing when and how to use
面具 但知道何时以及如何使用
this is kind of the harder part of
这是最难的部分
making that right judgement call of
做出正确的判断
using the right tool for the job anyway
无论如何
leave your questions comments below if
在下面留下您的问题评论
you have any and look forward to
你有任何 并期待
catching you in the next video
在下一个视频中捕捉到你